Contact

martinaraquel@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/martinagallagher-4685809 (LinkedIn) www.nianow.com/ (Other)

Top Skills

Nursing Teaching Clinical

Martina Gallagher

Psychiatric Nurse Practitioner at Progressive behavioral health Houston, Texas

Summary

Over 30 years of combined nursing experience in the areas of health care academics, interventional radiology, psychiatry, and emergency care. Excellent skills in the areas of problem-solving, team collaborations and focus on customer service. Strong skills in nursing research and education, especially online teaching, and program development. An advocate for social justice and health equity. Strong interest in mental health issues. Creative out of the box thinker. Always open to new growth opportunities.

Experience

Progressive Behavioral Health, PLLC
Psychiatric Nurse Practitioner
February 2020 - Present (5 months)

Houston, Texas, United States

Cizik School of Nursing at UTHealth 10 years 10 months

Associate Professor September 2016 - Present (3 years 10 months) Houston, Texas

Director Global Health Programs August 2015 - Present (4 years 11 months)

Coordinator of Honors Program
August 2013 - December 2019 (6 years 5 months)

Lead Coordinator for Undergraduate Community Clinical August 2014 - May 2019 (4 years 10 months)
Houston, T

Assistant Professor September 2009 - August 2016 (7 years) 6901 Bertner Ave. Houston, TX 77030 Universidad de Murcia Visiting Professor April 2013 - Present (7 years 3 months) Murcia, Spain

The University of Texas Medical Branch Assistant Professor December 2007 - August 2009 (1 year 9 months) Galveston, TX

University of Washington Tacoma Adjunct Professor January 2006 - December 2007 (2 years) Tacoma, Washington

Virginia Mason Medical Center Radiology Nurse 2005 - 2007 (2 years)

San Antonio College Clinical Instructor September 2004 - December 2005 (1 year 4 months) San Antonio, Texas

School of Nursing Clinical Instructor 2003 - 2005 (2 years)

University Health System Radiology Nurse 2001 - 2005 (4 years) San Antonio, Texas

Favorite Nurses Staff relief nurse for ER 1998 - 2001 (3 years) San Antonio, Texas Area

Southwest Mental Health Pediatric Center Psychiatric Mental Health Nurse January 1998 - December 1999 (2 years) Methodist Hospital Staff ER Nurse and Rotating Charge Nurse 1990 - 1998 (8 years)

San Antonio, Texas Area

Education

The University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston (UTHealth)

Post Masters, Psychiatric/Mental Health Nurse/Nursing · (2017 - 2019)

New York University

PRIDE Fellow, Sleep Medicine · (2012 - 2014)

University of Washington

Postdoctoral Fellowship focused on Sleep and its impact on health \cdot (2005 - 2007)

UT Health San Antonio

PhD, Nursing with a focus on health promotion of Latino children · (2001 - 2005)

UT Health San Antonio

BSN-MSN, Community Healthcare System Administration, with minor in Nursing Education and Informatics · (1995 - 2001)